《越狱》前情提要K
Previously on Prison Break:
-罪名是什么？ -杀人未遂
- What are the charges? - Attempted murder.
检方也要控告他 杀害自己的母亲和继父
He's also arraigned for the murder of his mother and his stepfather,
不要把我当成犯人看待 你自己坏事也做了不少
Don't look at me like I'm some con. You're as crooked as scoliosis.
但我不会被抓到
I don't get caught.
你只能走到这里
This is as far as you go.
-别这样，兄弟 -你和我不是兄弟
- Come on, bro. - You and I, we're not bros.
（圣路易 256里）
你打算何时告诉我们钱的事？
When were you planning on telling us about the money?
-什么钱？ -五百万美金
- What money? - Five million dollars...
威莫兰埋在 犹他州沙漠里的钱
...that Westmoreland planted in the desert in Utah.
我跟史泰门在一起 林克，他还活着
I found steadman. I'm with him now, Linc. He's alive.
什么？你找到史泰门了？
What? You found steadman?
天啊
Oh, my God.
我的手放在箱子里好几小时 快废掉了
My hand has been in that box for hours now. It is dying.
-我无法给你保证 -这是我的人生写照
- I can promise you nothing. - Story of my life.
-这是什么？ -有辆车在等我们
- And these? - The keys to a car that's waiting for us.
-在几百码外 -是两人座还是五人座？
- A couple hundred yards. - That a two-of-us or a five-of-us?
-是两人座 -有人来了
- That's a two-of-us. - We got company.
他怎么会知道？
How did he know?
我们迟早会知道 史柯菲脑中的计划
It's only a matter of time before we know everything that is in Scofield's head,
他的逃亡地点、逃亡的方式
Where he plans to run to, how he plans to get there,
等他真的来到该地点
So when the time comes that he does get there,,,
我们会在那里等着他
...we'll be waiting for him.
加拿大和墨西哥边境巡警 已经收到照片
Canadian and Mexican border patrols have all the mug shots,
边境巡警精锐部队 已提高警戒
BORTAc's on high alert,
看能否请墨西哥边境巡警 在五十里远处设立检查点
see if we can get the Mexican border patrol to set up checkpoints 50 miles in.
福克斯河典狱长打电话来 要求要知道所有行动
The warden over at Fox River called, asked to be kept in the loop,
-我该怎么回答他？ -他已没资格参与了
- What should I tell him? - That he's no longer in it.
你要的资料在你桌上 等你回来看
That info that you asked for is on your desk when you get in.
谢谢
Thank you,
（追缉福克斯河八人帮）
我们打算怎么做？
What's the plan, man?
这里不是监狱 要做什么随便你们
No bars on these doors. Do what you like.
我们能做什么？
With what?
我们原本现在应该在墨西哥 喝着鸡尾酒
We're supposed to be in Mexico, sipping on margaritas...
等待事过境E 原本计划是这样子的
...waiting for the heat to dip. That was the plan.
看吧？他们利用我们挖洞 我们只负责挖地洞
See? They just used us to dig, right? We're gophers.
-麦可在哪里？ -待会儿就来
- Where's Michael? - He'll be here.
好吧，对了，苏克
Okay. You know what, sucre?
也许你和我该去挖那五百万美金 懂我的意思吗？
Maybe you and I should go and get that $5 million, you know what I'm saying?
-钱就在犹他州图尔，等着出来透透气 -你想留下就闭嘴！
- It's sitting there in Tooele, ready to get. - You wanna stay, shut your mouth.
-警告你不准再碰我！ -两位，别激动
- You've got one more time to touch me. - Guys, chill.
-不然怎样？ -怎么了？
- What? - Hey!
沉住气
Relax.
老婆，你确定东西都带了吗？
Honey, are you sure you packed everything?
真好吃
Yummy.
报纸上有我们的照片 新闻应该都有报导
Our photos are in the paper. They're all over the news.
对，你没想到会这样吗？
Yeah, and you didn't see that coming?
-有什么好笑的？ -你们俩真幽默
- What's so funny? - The two of you. Cracks me up.
敬两位业余逃犯
Here's to amateur hour.
-你是怎么说的？干杯？ -尽管笑吧
- What do you say? - Yeah, yuk it up, funnyman.
（柏劳之子听证会已定）
各位，这是最后的晚餐
Last supper, boys.
现在我们该分道扬镖了
This is the part where we say goodbye.
钱不多
It's not much.
但足够你们上路了
It's enough to get you started.
-这个K -不行
- Hey... - No.
-我不会告诉你费班纳奇在哪里 -我又没问你
- I'm not telling you where Fibonacci is. - Well, I didn't ask.
我只要两毛五打电话
I only ask for a quarter for a phone call.
给一块
Make four.
谢谢
Thank you.
不知道其他人的情况如何
I wonder what happened to the other guys.
他们提早上路逃亡了 除了茶包
They all had a head start. Except for T-Bag.
对K他流了很多血
Yeah, he was bleeding pretty bad.
你觉得他死了吗？
Think he's dead?
完成了吗？
Are you done?
-还没，还得清理 -但算是完成了？
- No, I still have to clean it. - But you're done?
对
Yes.
该出发了
It's time to move,
东西都准备齐全
We got everything we need.
到犹他州短暂停留 然后前往墨西哥
Just a quick stop in Utah and then we're off to Mexico.
今天的听证会要决定 罗杰是否当作成人受审
L.J. Has a hearing today to determine if he gets tried as an adult.
我可以去救他
I can get him.
-现在时机不适合 -何时才适合？
- It's not the right time. - When will it be?
等我们到了墨西哥 等新闻不再报导我们
After we go to Mexico. After we're off the news.
他被栽赃两项谋杀罪
They framed him for a double homicide.
等他输掉听证会 马上会被送去成人监狱
Soon as he loses his hearing, they're gonna ship him out.
今天到法院 是我唯一能救他的机会
So today in the courthouse is my only chance to get him.
他们杀了哩诺卡 我不准他们夺走我儿子
They took Veronica. They're not gonna take my son.
我知道K
I know.
我知道
我绝不会丢下罗杰不管
I would never leave L.J. Behind.
可是现在没办法 我们事先没有计划
But we can't do this now. There's no plan in place.
相信我，我很熟悉法院
Believe me, I know that courthouse.
我去过的次数多到数不清
I've been there more times than I can remember.
只有一个法警会看着他 带着辣椒喷雾和一根棍子
The person guarding him's the bailiff. He carries Mace and a stick.
你打算大闹法院 这就是你的计划
So you're gonna bum-rush the courthouse. That's your plan.
-你是说真的？ -对
- Are you serious? - Yeah.
两位，我们要出发了
Hey, y'all, we're headed out, man.
祝各位好运
Well, good luck to everyone.
-不要惹麻烦 -知道了
- Stay out of trouble. - Yeah.
我要走了，老哥
This is it, papi.
-希望你找到女友，伙伴 -我只剩下她了
- I hope you find the girl, buddy. - She's all I have.
我会不顾一切地找
I'll die trying.
-祝你好运 -好，保重
- Good luck. - Yeah, you be easy, man.
也许我们还会再见面
Maybe we'll see each other again.
很难说，麦可
You never know, Michael.
这种事很难说
You never know.
把你记得的法院的事 全都告诉我
Tell me everything you know about the courthouse.
片名：越狱风云
剧名：火线电梯
-你有睡吗？ -几小时而已
- You get any sleep? - Couple hours.
竟然有八个人，真不敢相信
Eight of them. I still can't believe it.
这就是女人不能到军队 或警界工作的铁证
This is exhibit A why you don't let women work in the military or the police force...
男子监狱更是不行 因为你看这是什么后果？
...especially inside a male prison. Because look what you get.
甜心医生替史柯菲打开门
Dr. Sweetcheeks leaves the door open for scofield.
-就变成这样 -我觉得他们越狱另有原因K
- And here we are. - Sounds like there's more to the escape...
如果丹奎迪把医务室的门锁好
If Tancredi doesn't leave her office door unlocked...
这八个混蛋 现在还会在监狱里，懂吗？
...those eight dirtbags would be in the sHU right now, okay?
-这才是重点！ -布拉德
- Bottom line! - Brad.
-有新消息吗？ -没有
- Any update? - None.
他们最后出现在 奥斯威哥的墓园
They were last seen at that cemetery in oswego.
我们去抓他们 他们会去抓他们
- We'll get them. - They'll get them.
-案子已经移交给联邦调查局了 -不代表我们不能参与
- It's been handed to the FBI. - Doesn't mean we can't work it.
那代表我们不能参与
It does, actually.
-你和我已经无权参与逮捕行动 -为什么？
- You and I have been pulled off the pursuit. - Why?
马上就会知道 我们要回矫正局总部报到
We're going to find out shortly. We have to report to DoC headquarters.
-待会儿见K -长官，我们可以抓到他们
- I will meet you there. - Sir, we can get these guys.
-只要再给我几天，我一定会K -布拉德！
- Give me a couple more days and I swear l... - Brad.
我们得出发了
We've got to go.
帕托西克没有家人？ 一个也没有？
No family with Patoshik? Nothing?
对，四年前 他就杀光了自己的家人
Yeah. Until about four years ago, when he killed them all.
阿普斯基的前科纪录有更新 有机会时看一下
Updated rap sheet on Apolskis. Take a look when you get a chance.
（密苏里州，圣路易）
你得用放在烤架上的钥匙 因为那是K
You have to use the key that we keep in the grill because that's...
天啊，对不起
Man, I'm so sorry.
是我不好，老哥
It's my bad. My bad, bro.
对不起
I'm sorry.
史考特寇布雷纳
"Scott Kolbrenner."
就是这辆车
It's this one here.
不要碰收音机
Don't touch the radio.
我是《第蒙记事报》的记者 要采访罗杰柏劳的听证会
Yeah, hi. I'm with the Des Moines Herald, I'm covering the L.J. Burrows hearing.
请问是几点开始？
What time's that start today?
快点
Come on.
谢谢，是三点 听证会顶多持续半小时
Thank you. Three o'clock. The hearing lasts a half-hour max.
他在三点五十分会被带到转运室 好搭上四点的车
He'll be taken down to Transport Bay at 10 till to catch the 4:00 van.
我们要怎么接近他？
So how do we get close to him?
我被关起来的时候 只能猛看案情摘要
Well, when I was locked up, I had nothing to do except study the briefs.
每一本封面都有 尼克沙弗林的律师编号
Nick savrinn's bar number was on the front page of every one.
想要跟罗杰说话 只需要K
We wanna talk to L.J., we...
-假扮成他的律师 -对
- We pose as one of his attorneys. - Yeah.
荒唐，真是一派胡言
Hogwash, That is absolute hogwash,
请你回答问题
Please answer the question.
史柯菲怎么有办法 和你单独相处K
How was scofield able to have exclusive access to you...
对你动刀 把你绑在椅子上？
...pull a shank on you and bind you to your chair?
你可是堂堂的典狱长
The warden of the penitentiary.
我信任他
I trusted him.
显然他背叛了我的信任
Obviously, he betrayed that trust.
贝里克狱警
Officer Bellick...
这些越狱或试图越狱的犯人 是否全部都是K
...is it true that almost all the inmates who either escaped or tried to escape...
-监狱工厂的工人？ -没错
...worked in Prison Industries? - That's right.
这些犯人为何有时间
Why did these inmates have so much time...
在监狱工厂工作时K
...to dig a hole in the floor of the guards' room...
-在狱警休息室内挖洞？ -我来回答
...while working Prison Industries? - I can answer that.
恕我直言，如果你们 有在监狱工作的经验
If any of you have ever worked a day in a prison...
就会了解犯人的时薪 只有十九分钱
...you would know since an inmate gets 19 cents an hour...
有些人一定会偷懒
...some are bound to drag their feet.
贝里克狱警
Officer Bellick...
据说贿赂金额最高的人 就能管理监狱工厂？
...is it true you sold the right to run Prison Industries to the highest bidder?
-没有，是谁告诉你的？ -真是荒唐
- No. Who the hell told you that? - This is unbelievable.
当我们在此浪费时间 外面有八个逃犯K
While we're wasting time in here, there are eight escaped convicts out there...
葛瑞先生 你是否当过福克斯河的狱警？
Were you employed at Fox River as a correctional officer, Mr. Geary?
-是的 -没错K
- Yep. - Yeah...
直到他因为勒索犯人 而被开除
...until he was fired for shaking down inmates.
请不要插话，狱警
That'll be your last outburst, officer.
你是否知道贝里克狱警 因监狱工厂一事
Were you aware of any arrangement officer Bellick had...
和犯人有任何协议？
...with any inmate regarding Prison Industries?
对，他把工作 卖给约翰亚布兹
Yeah, he sold it to John Abruzzi.
约翰亚布兹 他也是逃犯之一？
John Abruzzi, who is one of the escaped convicts?
对
Yep.
若有必要 我们会请其他狱警作证
We'll get other C.o.'s to substantiate this if we have to...
所以我给你一次机会 先说清楚
...so I'm giving you one chance to get in front of it.
你是否把监狱工厂 卖给约翰亚布兹？
Did you sell Prison Industries to John Abruzzi?
有还是没有？
Yes or no?
-有，但当时我完全不知情K -就这样，贝里克狱警
- Yes. But at no time was I aware of... - That'll be all, officer Bellick.
就这样！
That will be all.
典狱长，请你和 贝里克狱警到走廊上
Warden, you and officer Bellick can step out into the hallway.
等我们裁决完会通知你们
We'll call for you when we've reached a decision.
我要去喝杯咖啡
I'm gonna get some coffee.
在这种情况下，我尽力了
Well, I did my best under the circumstances.
先生，好消息是 你把手冰冻了起来
The good news, sir, is you had the hand iced...
所以血液可以流通 骨头也固定了
...so I was able to restore blood flow and the bones are pinned.
但我还是建议你立刻就医
However, I recommend you get medical attention AsAP.
现在你要服用阿斯匹灵 可以稀释血液，以免阻塞
Meanwhile, some aspirin. It'll help thin the blood and avoid clotting.
还有抗生素、止痛药
Antibiotics, some painkillers.
通常我会告诉猫、狗的主人K
I usually tell the owner of the dog, cat, whatever...
把药涂上花生酱 让宠物比较容易嚼
...to coat them with peanut butter so they're easier to chew.
-但显然你不需要K -辛苦你了，医生
- But obviously, in your case... - You did one hell of a job, doc.
谢谢
Well, thank you.
你现在可以走了
Well, it's okay for you to leave now.
我会走的
Oh, I'm leaving.
-但是你不能走 -什么？
- And you're not. - What?
-你听到了 -先生，我什么也没看到K
- You heard me. - Look, sir, I haven't seen anything...
也不会告诉任何人
...and I won't tell anyone.
我以前曾经被这些谎话骗过
You know, I fell for that bill of goods once before.
我不会再上当了
Never again.
-先生，我发誓我不会说出去 -你会的
- Sir, I swear to God I will tell nobody. - You would.
而我会死在狱中
And I would die in prison.
求求你K不要K
Please, please, please.
你替我好好的动了手术 现在我要回报你
Now, you did me a solid, so I'm gonna return the favor.
如果你不反抗 我就会仁慈点
This can go down humanely if you don't fight.
但是如果你又想逃跑 我马上会变得很残忍
But if you pull a stunt like that again, it's gonna get inhumane right quick.
你自己决定
Your call.
不过无论你怎么选择
But one way or another...
你都是死路一条，医生
...I am putting you down, doc.
（伊利诺州芝加哥 库克郡立法院）
- Lincoln Burrows Jr? - Yeah.
-罗杰柏劳？ -我是
进去，你有访客
In here. You got a visitor.
（严禁吸烟）
You must be L.J.
你一定是罗杰
我是联邦调查局的曼宏探员
Agent Mahone, FBI. Thank you.
请坐
Please.
我想你已经听说了
I'm assuming you've heard.
对
Yeah.
我得说，你爸和叔叔做的事K
I have to tell you, what your dad and uncle pulled off...
相当令人佩服 我当探员已有十四年K
Very impressive. I've been doing this 14 years...
越狱案例大多都要 归功于好运气或蛮力
...and most escapes can be attributed to dumb luck or brute force.
他们的计划 缜密周详的程度
The level of planning and sophistication that went into this one...
加上八个人逃出去
...and eight guys got out...
以专业角度来看 我真的K
I really do, professionally speaking...
很钦佩林克和麦可
...have a lot of admiration for Lincoln and Michael.
很好，我们可以当好朋友
Cool. Now we're buddies.
找我什么事？
What do you need?
帮助我以和平的方式 逮捕他们
Help me bring them in peacefully.
我不知道他们在哪里
I don't know where they are.
-也不知道他们要去哪里 -你还有其他方式可以帮忙
- I don't know where they're going. - There's another way you can help.
-怎么帮？ -上电视
- How? - Go on TV.
半小时内 我就能请转播小组过来
I can have a camera crew down here in a half an hour.
你知道吗？ 他们栽赃我爸谋杀罪
You know what, man? The murder charge they put on my dad...
又栽赃我两项谋杀罪
...the two murder charges they put me...
一切都是政府高层的设计
...everything's been a setup, coming from way up top.
所以既然你是政府人员
So the fact that you work for the government...
我无话可说
I got nothing to say.
我现在给你 楼下餐厅的人也会给的建议
I'll give you the same advice that you'd get from the guy working at the deli downstairs.
开始替你自己设想
Start thinking about yourself now.
事实上，越快越好
In fact, the sooner the better, because no one...
罗杰，因为其他人没办法 你父亲K
...not your father, L.J., not your uncle...
你叔叔都不会帮你坐牢
...is going to do your time.
你现在才十六岁 刑期会非常长
And at 16 years old, you're looking at a long stretch.
你会被判多少年？ 要去哪里坐牢？
How much time you get, where you serve it...
你的狱友会是谁？
...who your cellmate might be.
你现在必须替自己设想
You need to start thinking about yourself now.
我要逮捕你父亲和叔叔 我愿意谈条件
I want your dad, I want your uncle, and I'm willing to deal.
不要让大好机会白白飞了
Don't wait and let someone else get the reward.
干嘛？
What's up?
老兄，你很眼熟
Hey, man, you look familiar.
你上学期有参加 兄弟会招募吗？
Did you rush sig Ep last semester?
-兄弟什么？ -兄弟会
- Sig what? - Sig Ep.
-没有 -下一位
- No. - Next in line.
要去哪里？
Where to?
犹他州
Utah.
（柏劳越狱 其他七人在逃）
有班次吗？
How we doing here?
明天才有班次
Nothing until tomorrow.
好吧，我有四十五元
All right, yo, I got 45 bucks.
这样搭车最远能到哪一站？
How far will that get me?
（柏劳越狱 其他七人在逃）
尼克沙弗林 律师编号56437
Nick savrinn. Bar number is 56437.
我和我的当事人 罗杰柏劳有约
I got a call time with my client, L.J. Burrows.
-喂 -知道我是谁吧？
- Hello. - Know who this is?
知道
Yeah.
知道，尼克沙弗林
Yeah, Nick savrinn.
你还好吗？
How you holding up?
尽量撑着
Doing what I can do.
你呢？
How about you?
我很担心你
I'm worried about you.
-抱歉让你受这些苦 -谢谢
- I'm sorry about what you're going through. - Thanks,
听说听证会结束后 因为我爸现在很出名
Word is after this hearing, because of my dad being so high-profile...
他们要送我去成人监狱 在亚利桑那州京曼
...they're shipping me to an adult facility in Kingman, Arizona.
希望这件事不会成真
Yeah, well, hopefully that ain't gonna happen.
哩诺卡 今天有和你联络吗？
You hear from Veronica today?
她没有出现 法院指派一个烂律师给我
She didn't show up. They gave me some court-appointed clown.
没有，她没有和我连络
No, I haven't heard from her.
对了，今天有个 调查局探员来找我
Hey, this fed came by and talked to me today.
是吗？
Yeah?
他要我帮忙 请我爸去自首
He wanted me to help try in getting my dad to turn himself in,
我认识你爸 他不可能去自首
Well, knowing your dad, I doubt that's gonna happen.
听着罗杰，这件事很重要
Listen up, L.J., this is real important.
-好 -注意三楼的“奥的斯佑芳”
- All right. - On the third, look out for otis Wright.
听到了吗？ 注意三楼的“奥的斯佑芳”
You got that? On the third, look out for Otis Wright,
在那之前 记得把头抬高
Until then, keep your head up.
-什么？ -记住就是了
- What? - Just remember that,
我会尽全力救你出来
I'm gonna do everything I can to get you out.
尼克
Hey, Nick.
如果你遇到我爸
If you talk to my dad...
告诉他不管发生什么事 我都爱他
,,, tell him no matter what, I love him,
-你好 -你好
- Hey. - Hey.
-告诉他了吗？ -行动吧
- Did you get him? - Let's do this.
我们还得去一个地方
We got one more stop.
我的信仰中有个观念 我相当确信
There is a belief in my religion which I know to be true...
不论是否为印度教徒 人人都适用
...and it applies to everyone, Hindu or not.
人此生的行为会影响下辈子
The acts we commit in this life determine where we go in the next.
犯下恶行的人 将永世无法得到幸福
And he who commits evil can never hope for eternal happiness.
那不是我的目标，医生
Never been a goal of mine, doc.
我比较关心现在的人生
I'm more a here-and-now type.
我告诉你一件我确信的事
I'll tell you something I know is true.
本国拿战斧的印地安人K
The Indians here, the tomahawk variety...
有些人相信K
...some of them believe...
应该说曾经相信 因为他们都死光了
Well, used to believe, before most of them were slaughtered.
当战士在战场上 杀死另一个战士
- That when a warrior kills another in battle...
他会吸取死去战士的灵魂
...he absorbs that fallen warrior's spirit.
所以这不是 你生命的尽头，医生
So this isn't the end for you, doc.
你会与我同在
You're with me now.
你今天好吗？
And how are you doing this fine day?
我很好，你好吗？
I'm great. How are you?
再好不过了 需要我帮忙找东西吗？
Couldn't be better. Anything in particular I can help you find?
我只是随便看看，谢谢
Just looking. Thanks.
如果需要帮忙 叫一声就好
Well, if you need any assistance, just give a holler.
-你今天好吗？ -很好
- How are we this fine day? - Great.
-需要帮忙吗？ -不用，谢谢
- Can I help you find anything? - I'm good, thanks.
我们得走了
Hey, we gotta go.
-等我付帐 -不行
- I just need to pay up. - Now.
你好吗，警官？
How are you today, officer?
对，他们就在K
Yeah, they were right...
他们原本在后面的
Well, they were right back here.
我们可以从这里走路去法院
We can make it to the courthouse on foot.
你不懂，所有东西都在车上
You don't understand. Everything is in that car.
别管车子，我们没时间了
Forget the damn car. We don't have time.
我们快走吧
Come on, man, let's go.
-你好 -你好
- Hi. - Hi.
（共乘布告板）
（开车回犹他州，别笑
想找人共乘分摊开支
黛伯拉珍贝尔 801-555-0199）
本裁决会决定 波普典狱长K
It is the finding of this panel, Warden Pope...
扣除两周薪水 且留职观察三个月
...you'll be docked two weeks, placed on three months' probation.
布拉德贝里克狱警K
Officer Brad Bellick...
你被革职了，立即生效
...will be terminated, effective immediately.
贝里克先生，你可以回福克斯河 收拾私人物品
Mr. Bellick, you can retrieve whatever belongings you may have from Fox River.
就这样
That'll be all.
我K从十八岁起 就在福克斯河监狱工作
I've worked at Fox River since I was 18 years old.
当狱警是我的一切
Being a C.o. Is my life.
我们很感激你
And we appreciate that.
我们大可省下很多时间K
We could've saved a lot of time if you would've just told us...
如果你们 从一开始说清楚的话
...that this was gonna be a railroad.
-就这样了 -这次越狱事件只能归咎一个人
- That'll be all. - There is only one person responsible...
他叫做麦可史柯菲
...for this escape. His name is Michael scofield.
错不在贝里克狱警或我身上！
It's not officer Bellick. It's not me!
如果你们要代罪羔羊 没关系
But you need a fall guy, fine.
但是我不会 只让贝里克丢掉工作
But you're not gonna be just taking officer Bellick's job.
即使他的许多行为 让我颜面尽失
Because even though I am not proud of many of his actions...
但如果我不照顾我的下属 我就未免太冷血无情了
...it will be a cold day in hell when I turn my back on one of my own men.
我辞职
I quit.
就这样
That will be all.
如果行动不成功 你被抓回福克斯河监狱
If this thing doesn't work out and you end up going back to Fox River...
我可不会去救你
...I ain't coming to get you.
毕竟有脑袋的是你 我只有蛮力
I mean, you are the brains and I am the brute.
麦可，说真的 你不必非要帮忙不可
Seriously, Michael, you don't have to do this.
我们走
Let's go.
（氧化染料）
（双氧水）
你可以出去了
We're good.
今天稍早尼克沙弗林打电话给你 这是怎么回事？
You got a call from Nick savrinn earlier today. What was that all about?
他是我的律师 这是律师与客户之间的秘密
He's my attorney. That's privileged.
真奇怪 因为那通电话打来前一小时
That's odd, because Nick savrinn was found dead in his apartment...
尼克沙弗林被发现 陈尸在家中
...an hour before that call came into you.
-听着罗杰，这件事很重要 -好
- Listen up, L, J,, this is real important, - All right,
注意三楼的“奥的斯佑芳” 听到了吗？
On the third, look out for Otis Wright, You got that?
你既然如此确信 政府能做出K
For someone who's convinced the government is capable...
许多狡诈的事 你未免也太不小心了
...of so many underhanded things, you sure are playing fast and loose with me.
你打算怎么做？ 再栽赃我一项谋杀罪？
What are you gonna do, throw another fake murder charge on me?
-奥的斯佑芳是谁？ -我不知道
- Who's otis Wright? - I have no idea.
我想你知道 如果你不告诉我，你被定罪后
I think you do. And if you don't tell me, after you're convicted...
判刑时我会到法庭旁听 眼睁睁看你去送死
...I will be in that courtroom when you're sentenced, and I will hang you out to dry.
我向你保证
Take it to the bank.
帮我连络 起诉罗杰柏劳案的检察官
Yeah, put me in touch with the prosecutor in the L.J. Burrows case.
我要和他见面
I want a meeting.
注意三楼的“奥的斯佑芳”
On the third, look out for Otis Wright,
在那之前 记得把头抬高
Until then, keep your head up,
（奥的斯电梯公司）
“奥的斯佑芳”
Otis Wright,
-走吧 -等等
- Let's go. - Hold on.
-走了 -等一下
- Move it. - Hold on.
我送他去
I'll escort the boy.
奥的斯佑芳 右方的奥的斯电梯
Otis Wright. Otis elevator on the right.
他打算怎么做？
What is he planning?
不拔枪就不会有人受伤
Keep it in the holster and no one gets hurt.
不准拔枪
Keep it in the holster.
很好，罗杰，把电梯停住
All right. L.J., hit stop.
他要跟我们走 不要轻举妄动
He's coming with us, so just stay cool. Stay cool.
小子，把他的枪给我
Hey, buddy, give me his gun.
你小心点
Hey, hey.
罗杰，把手伸出来
L.J., give me your hand.
很好，过来
Thattaboy. Come on.
退后！退后！
Hey, back off. Back off. Back off.
你不敢开枪，你也一样
You're not shooting anybody. Neither are you.
去自首，我就放了你的儿子
Give yourself up and your kid can walk.
只有这样他才不必坐牢 这是唯一的办法
That's the only way he's getting out of this place. It's the only way.
爸
Dad.
Dad!
-爸，放开我的手 -不
- Dad, you gotta let me go. - No.
爸
Dad.
你要放开我
You gotta let me go.
上面！史柯菲在大楼里 去抓他
Up there. Scofield is in the building. Take him.
你们负责那一边 史柯菲和柏劳在大楼里！
You guys, go. Cover that way. Scofield and Burrows are in the building.
过来
Come on.
-站住！ -不准动！
- Freeze! - Don't move!
-上卡车 -站住！我们会开枪！
- Truck. - Stop or we will shoot.
站住！
Stop!
（办公室家具行）
两名嫌犯在自由街向南逃
Two suspects heading south on Liberty.
布拉德
Bradley?
什么事，妈？
Yeah, Ma?
你怎么这么早就回家？
What are you doing home so early?
我得K把假用掉
Well, I had to take...
以免假期过期了
...my personal days, you know, before they went away.
你不用追捕逃犯吗？
Shouldn't you be looking for the convicts?
有其他人在侦办，妈
Well, they got somebody else doing that, Ma.
你还好吗？
You okay?
我很好
I'm good.
那就好
Okay.
太好了
All right.
我们应该在上面 敲破香槟瓶来庆祝
We should break a bottle of champagne across its bow.
如果你打算今晚把这运回家 当结婚纪念日礼物
If you're intending to get this home for your anniversary tonight...
-我建议你别这么做 -也对
...I wouldn't recommend it. - No.
听着，我想告诉你K
Listen, I want you to know, I...
我K很荣幸认识你
Well, I feel very fortunate to have met you.
我要越狱逃出去
I'm breaking out.
你要帮助我哥 和我一起逃出去
And you're gonna make sure my brother goes with me.
（马文古达兽医诊所）
感谢您使用智慧导航系统K 古达医生，我没有念错吧？
Thank you for calling AutoStar, Dr, Gudat, Am I pronouncing that correctly?
-非常正确 -有事需要效劳吗？
- Dead on. - How can I help you today?
我需要K方向引导
I need directions.
-目的地是哪里，先生？ -犹他州
- Where to, sir? - Utah.
不好意思
Excuse me.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你是史考特寇布雷纳吗？
Are you scott Kolbrenner?
对，就是我
I am, yeah.
你一定是黛伯拉珍
You must be Debra Jean.
-很高兴认识你 -我也是
- It's nice to meet you. - Yeah, same here.
真巧，你打电话来时 我正要离开
I was almost ready to leave when you called.
没有半个人回应
No one else responded.
我想这里很少犹他州人吧 你是犹他州人吗？
I guess there's not a lot of Utah people out here. Are you from there?
不是，我K
No, I just, you know...
我要去继承遗产
I'm headed out there to collect an inheritance.
-我爷爷死了 -我很遗憾
- My grandpa died. - Oh, I'm sorry to hear that.
没关系 他走得轰轰烈烈
It's all right. He went out with his boots on.
你的行李在哪里？
So where's your stuff?
我昨天寄过去了
I mailed it yesterday.
用寄的？我没听过这种事
Mailed it? I've never heard of that.
带着到处跑不方便 而且我认识快递公司的朋友
You don't wanna lug it around. Plus, I got a boy who works for UPs.
他就帮我寄了
So he hooked it up.
你要出发了吗？
So you wanna bounce?
好，我的车在前面
Okay. I'm parked out front.
布拉德？
Bradley?
什么事，妈？
Yeah, Ma?
电视上刚刚宣布赏金
They just announced the rewards on the TV.
-什么赏金？ -那些逃犯
- What reward? - The convicts.
就是抓到越狱逃犯的赏金
For the convicts. The ones who escaped.
-多少钱？ -一人十万美金
- How much? - A hundred thousand dollars apiece.
谋杀雷诺兹总统弟弟的禽兽 赏金有三十万美金
Three hundred thousand for the animal who killed President Reynolds' brother.
现在全国上下的疯子 都会开始追捕这些家伙
Every whacko in the country's gonna be after those bums now...
不是吗？
...wouldn't you say?
警察！
Police!
双手举高，下车！
Step out of the vehicle with your hands up.
-我们得快点离开 -我没办法
- We gotta move. - I can't.
天啊
Oh, my God.
我救不了他
I failed him.
希望你带了午餐 到亚利桑那州的路程非常远
I sure hope you packed a lunch. It's gonna be a long ride to Arizona.
过去
Move your ass.
派人到附近所有的医院 不管在哪里，其中一个伤得不轻
Get men in all the area hospitals. Wherever they are, one of them's bleeding good.
所以如果他们不自首 就只能等死
Which means they either come to us or they die.